<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orchestrator on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/categories/orchestrator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Orchestrator on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2019–2021, Fletcher Kelly; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 12:19:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/categories/orchestrator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a VM – SCSM, SCVMM, SCORCH – all working in harmony</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-07-31-deploy-a-vm-scsm-scvmm-scorch-all-working-in-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 12:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-07-31-deploy-a-vm-scsm-scvmm-scorch-all-working-in-harmony/</guid>
      <description>So, it has been a while.
So, the requirement for this project was as follow.
 Use Service Manager. Provide a portal for logging a VM Creation request. Build the computername based on a predetermined pattern. Determine first available name. Perform a capacity check. Deploy the set number of VMs.  I am going to skip over the first 2 Points, there are numerous topics covering this. So, onto point 3, I created a Service Request Extension, if anyone would like some info on this, also plenty of articles, please let me know and I can do a blog post on the Extension, or I can make the extension available for you to seal yourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Comments to Work Items with Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-04-04-adding-comments-to-work-items-with-orchestrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 08:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-04-04-adding-comments-to-work-items-with-orchestrator/</guid>
      <description>Hi All,
It has been a little while, i have been quite involved with an Integration Project. With this project there was a requirement to add comments to a Work Item. The information is passed on from &amp;ldquo;System A&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;System B&amp;rdquo; via XML. Using PowerShell, extracting the XML contents is not too difficult, if anyone would like to dive into that a little bit, please let me know with Comments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
