<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>import on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/import/</link>
    <description>Recent content in import on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2019–2021, Fletcher Kelly; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 05:10:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/import/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Import CI Items with Cireson Asset Import Tool</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/05/17/import-ci-items-with-cireson-asset-import-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 05:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/05/17/import-ci-items-with-cireson-asset-import-tool/</guid>
      <description>With my previous post about importing data, I showed you how to use the built-in CSV connector to do this task and how to create the required Projection Classes. However if you are looking for a quicker more automated to achieve this, enter Cireson and their Asset Import Tool. It takes all the guess work out of the import process and handles the Projection Classes for you.
The installation of the application is easy and requires the copying a DLL file to the Service Manager Installation folder and the import of a Management Pack ( a management Pack Bundle in this case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing data into Service Manager–CSV import and XML</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/04/23/importing-data-into-service-managercsv-import-and-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 05:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/04/23/importing-data-into-service-managercsv-import-and-xml/</guid>
      <description>So, just recently I was asked by a customer to import data from an “old” SCSM system. The customer is moving to new hardware within the organization and is using this opportunity to clean up Service Manager and re-import only clean data.So, the challenge is the following.The customer wants to import Change Requests from the “old” Service Manager to the “new” Service Manager. Ok, so after some research and confirmation, it is NOT possible to simply move data from one Service Manager installation to another.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
