<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Prtoection Manager on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/data-prtoection-manager/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Prtoection Manager on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2013–2021, Fletcher Kelly; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 15:13:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/data-prtoection-manager/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DPM and Invoke-Command, bring the DPM shell to your machine</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/06/15/dpm-and-invoke-command-bring-the-dpm-shell-to-your-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 15:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/06/15/dpm-and-invoke-command-bring-the-dpm-shell-to-your-machine/</guid>
      <description>Not that long ago, I created an article about DPM and I referenced DPM commands to be run in the DPM shell and only now realised that not everyone has the DPM console installed as this is not the easiest console to install and get working.
So, I am now the Proud Owner of Learn Windows PowerShell in a month of Lunches and I am an now playing and have figured out how to import the necessary commands with Remoting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing your Protection Server in DPM to another server</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/05/27/changing-your-protection-server-in-dpm-to-another-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 09:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/05/27/changing-your-protection-server-in-dpm-to-another-server/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been in a situation where you have either removed or added a new DPM server to your environment?
It happened to me just the other day, I had to “re-think” my DPM design and starting using “Local” to each Data Centre DPM servers to backup my data at each Data Centre. However, this was not the case before this, we were using the same product, but a different strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
