<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SCO on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/sco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SCO on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2019–2021, Fletcher Kelly; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 05:08:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/sco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grey Agent Fixing with Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2015-04-14-grey-agent-fixing-with-orchestrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 05:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2015-04-14-grey-agent-fixing-with-orchestrator/</guid>
      <description>So, here is the scenario, we managed a lot of customer’s System Centre Operations Manager (SCOM) environments. One of the most common issues we run into, it is the “Grey Agent” issue, where an agent is no longer reporting into SCOM. There might be a few reasons for this, however one of the most common and effective ways to fix this to clear the agent cache. By this, we simply mean connecting to the agent, stopping the “SCOM” service, deleting the content of the “Health Service State” folder and then restarting the “SCOM” service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a VM – SCSM, SCVMM, SCORCH – all working in harmony</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-07-31-deploy-a-vm-scsm-scvmm-scorch-all-working-in-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 12:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-07-31-deploy-a-vm-scsm-scvmm-scorch-all-working-in-harmony/</guid>
      <description>So, it has been a while.
So, the requirement for this project was as follow.
 Use Service Manager. Provide a portal for logging a VM Creation request. Build the computername based on a predetermined pattern. Determine first available name. Perform a capacity check. Deploy the set number of VMs.  I am going to skip over the first 2 Points, there are numerous topics covering this. So, onto point 3, I created a Service Request Extension, if anyone would like some info on this, also plenty of articles, please let me know and I can do a blog post on the Extension, or I can make the extension available for you to seal yourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End User Portal for System Centre Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/08/05/end-user-portal-for-system-centre-orchestrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 04:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/08/05/end-user-portal-for-system-centre-orchestrator/</guid>
      <description>So, let’s ay you have invested the time and gotten System Centre Orchestrator up and running in your environment and you have the product performing some day to day tasks and it is working well. However, now you want start using SCO (System Centre Orchestrator) to start performing end user focused tasks like Password Reset, add users to groups or even disabling of users or server testing as part of first line support.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
