<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DPM on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/dpm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DPM on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2013–2021, Fletcher Kelly; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 12:30:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/dpm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finding off site ready tapes for System Center Data Protection Manager with System Center Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/10/20/finding-off-site-ready-tapes-for-system-center-data-protection-manager-with-system-center-orchestrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 12:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/10/20/finding-off-site-ready-tapes-for-system-center-data-protection-manager-with-system-center-orchestrator/</guid>
      <description>So, I am quite a keen user of PowerShell and System Centre Orchestrator. Ok, so I recently had a request from a customer that went as follows “I need DPM to alert me when tapes are ready to be taken off-site.”
DPM does not seen to have this functionality out of the box within the Graphical User Interface (GUI). All is NOT lost, Data Protection Manager has a PowerShell component and i was sure i could figure out a way to get this to work within PowerShell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DPM and Exchange Mail Store Backup failing</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/08/13/dpm-and-exchange-mail-store-backup-failing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 10:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/08/13/dpm-and-exchange-mail-store-backup-failing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DPM and Invoke-Command, bring the DPM shell to your machine</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/06/15/dpm-and-invoke-command-bring-the-dpm-shell-to-your-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 15:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/06/15/dpm-and-invoke-command-bring-the-dpm-shell-to-your-machine/</guid>
      <description>Not that long ago, I created an article about DPM and I referenced DPM commands to be run in the DPM shell and only now realised that not everyone has the DPM console installed as this is not the easiest console to install and get working.
So, I am now the Proud Owner of Learn Windows PowerShell in a month of Lunches and I am an now playing and have figured out how to import the necessary commands with Remoting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing your Protection Server in DPM to another server</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/05/27/changing-your-protection-server-in-dpm-to-another-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 09:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/05/27/changing-your-protection-server-in-dpm-to-another-server/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been in a situation where you have either removed or added a new DPM server to your environment?
It happened to me just the other day, I had to “re-think” my DPM design and starting using “Local” to each Data Centre DPM servers to backup my data at each Data Centre. However, this was not the case before this, we were using the same product, but a different strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Protect or NOT to Protect</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/05/24/to-protect-or-not-to-protect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/05/24/to-protect-or-not-to-protect/</guid>
      <description>I have finally found some time to look some more into DPM and decided to modify my environment and created some additional PROTECTION GROUPS. I am particularly chuffed as I have not done this before. Make no error, I have used DPM extensively for mailbox recoveries (Execs and other users crying about loosing items), recovering of databases and VHD (see some of my previous posts). So back to my point, the Protection groups were created without any hassle and now I have a dedicated SharePoint Protection Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “crisis” week</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/05/03/the-crisis-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 08:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/05/03/the-crisis-week/</guid>
      <description>Hi All,
The last two weeks have been a little nutty for me. I have however, learnt to appreciate a few more things in life.
  No matter how good your planning for DR, there is always that one thing that catches you. We have a generator, which is great. Now, when we cutover from generator power to mains power and then the main building power trips, life becomes interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
