<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Fletcher&#39;s Cloud Journey</title>
    <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Fletcher&#39;s Cloud Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 12:41:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I want to use Azure VMware Solution, what should I know about networking?</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/p/i-want-to-use-azure-vmware-solution-what-should-i-know-about-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 12:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/p/i-want-to-use-azure-vmware-solution-what-should-i-know-about-networking/</guid>
      <description>What else do I need to know when using Azure VMware Solution (AVS)?
Networking Edition
I have been working with many customers over the last little while that are looking at Azure VMware Solution (AVS).
Often the idea and use case for the customer is correct. There are a few great reasons to use AVS. If you fit within the use cases, you are in for a real treat.
Deciding whether or not you are a fit is part of the equation, there is more to this scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Networking Azure</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/p/importance-of-networking-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 16:33:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/p/importance-of-networking-azure/</guid>
      <description>As a start to this blog post, I think it is important to understand how I see my role as a CSA (Cloud Solution Architect) with my customer. I am primarily a trusted advisor and my customers respect what I have to say, I question and challenge my customers in a constructive way to approach the challenge or problem statement in a different way. I have an amazing role of using Azure as my LEGO playpen and then building a custom solution (LEGO model) to help my customers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
