<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System Center on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/categories/system-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Center on Fletcher&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2013–2021, Fletcher Kelly; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 06:21:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/categories/system-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SLA Reporting with PowerShell and SCSM</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2015-08-27-sla-reporting-with-powershell-and-scsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 06:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2015-08-27-sla-reporting-with-powershell-and-scsm/</guid>
      <description>I always get asked about reporting from my customers, and specifically around SLA&amp;rsquo;s. SLA&amp;rsquo;s are very important to most companies as this is part of the tracking mechanism of employees and vendors and the like.
SMLETS is needed for this, it is built to be run from the server, if you need to run from your local machine, please install SMLets, copy the SDK Binaries folder and use the -computername where applicable with the SMLets commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grey Agent Fixing with Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2015-04-14-grey-agent-fixing-with-orchestrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 05:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2015-04-14-grey-agent-fixing-with-orchestrator/</guid>
      <description>So, here is the scenario, we managed a lot of customer’s System Centre Operations Manager (SCOM) environments. One of the most common issues we run into, it is the “Grey Agent” issue, where an agent is no longer reporting into SCOM. There might be a few reasons for this, however one of the most common and effective ways to fix this to clear the agent cache. By this, we simply mean connecting to the agent, stopping the “SCOM” service, deleting the content of the “Health Service State” folder and then restarting the “SCOM” service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a VM – SCSM, SCVMM, SCORCH – all working in harmony</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-07-31-deploy-a-vm-scsm-scvmm-scorch-all-working-in-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 12:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-07-31-deploy-a-vm-scsm-scvmm-scorch-all-working-in-harmony/</guid>
      <description>So, it has been a while.
So, the requirement for this project was as follow.
 Use Service Manager. Provide a portal for logging a VM Creation request. Build the computername based on a predetermined pattern. Determine first available name. Perform a capacity check. Deploy the set number of VMs.  I am going to skip over the first 2 Points, there are numerous topics covering this. So, onto point 3, I created a Service Request Extension, if anyone would like some info on this, also plenty of articles, please let me know and I can do a blog post on the Extension, or I can make the extension available for you to seal yourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cireson Outlook Console</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-06-17-cireson-outloook-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 06:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-06-17-cireson-outloook-console/</guid>
      <description>So, Cireson hase been investing into System Centre Service Manager (SCSM) very heavily and the end results are WELL worth it.
The Cireson Outlook Console has been out a little while, however it just keeps getting better and better. The Console is super easy to install. The Install instructions are provided by Cireson. There are a few steps to follow as well as the installation of an Outlook Plugin.
Yes, as you may have guessed from the name, this allows you to connect to Service Manager with almost a full experience directly from OUTLOOK, how great is that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Comments to Work Items with Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-04-04-adding-comments-to-work-items-with-orchestrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 08:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2014-04-04-adding-comments-to-work-items-with-orchestrator/</guid>
      <description>Hi All,
It has been a little while, i have been quite involved with an Integration Project. With this project there was a requirement to add comments to a Work Item. The information is passed on from &amp;ldquo;System A&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;System B&amp;rdquo; via XML. Using PowerShell, extracting the XML contents is not too difficult, if anyone would like to dive into that a little bit, please let me know with Comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send Email to 3rd Party from SCSM Console – PowerShell and Console Task</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2013-11-15-send-email-to-3rd-party-from-scsm-console-powershell-and-console-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 11:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2013-11-15-send-email-to-3rd-party-from-scsm-console-powershell-and-console-task/</guid>
      <description>So recently, I had a customer ask me for the following as their previous incident management system had this functionality.
The customer wanted to be able to send an &amp;ldquo;Update Email&amp;rdquo; to a 3rd party from the SCSM Console with automatically placing the reference number into said email. They needed the functionality of sending to any email address. This was a requirement for the type of business they are in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Request Load Testing for SCSM</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/09/11/service-request-load-testing-for-scsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 19:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/09/11/service-request-load-testing-for-scsm/</guid>
      <description>I have found a great for load testing SCSM with Incidents. The script uses SMLets to generate Incidents and you can then gauge how your system would handle the load you are planning within your Production Environment.
I will not go into the detail of the script as this blog post does a great job of explaining it. SO this got me to thinking about other Load Testing you could perform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End User Portal for System Centre Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/08/05/end-user-portal-for-system-centre-orchestrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 04:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/08/05/end-user-portal-for-system-centre-orchestrator/</guid>
      <description>So, let’s ay you have invested the time and gotten System Centre Orchestrator up and running in your environment and you have the product performing some day to day tasks and it is working well. However, now you want start using SCO (System Centre Orchestrator) to start performing end user focused tasks like Password Reset, add users to groups or even disabling of users or server testing as part of first line support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recover System Center Orchestrator 2012 with runbooks export</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/02/04/recover-system-center-orchestrator-2012-with-runbooks-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 11:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/02/04/recover-system-center-orchestrator-2012-with-runbooks-export/</guid>
      <description>Just recently in a test environment, a script or some such other gremlin caused some absolute havoc on my system. Before you ask, I had NO Backup in place of this system. This system was System Center Orchestrator. However, once a week, I do a “sort-of” backup. By this, I mean I export all my Runbooks and place a copy on my local machine and a file server and the SCORCH (System Center ORCHestrator) server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cireson Analyst Web Console</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/01/22/cireson-analyst-web-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 09:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2013/01/22/cireson-analyst-web-console/</guid>
      <description>I have always heard complaints from some of the analysts in my company about having to install the Service Manager Console on their machines and then complaining about having to learn a new application.
So, I went searching around and found a great application called Cireson SCSM Web Console, this allows analysts to update Incidents via a newly designed web portal for Analysts. Since the console is designed in HTML5, the web console is browser agnostic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group assignment with Service Manager</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2012-12-31-group-assignment-with-service-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 06:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/post/history/2012-12-31-group-assignment-with-service-manager/</guid>
      <description>So one of the biggest issues I have with Service Manager is actually user based as seems to be quite difficult to teach the concept of this for some strange reason. So, as a work-around I have created views that cater for the issue I am about to discuss.
The issue is as follows, when a Work Item gets re-assigned to a new Analyst, 99% of the time, the associated Support Group does NOT get changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConfigMgr (SCCM) 2012 wont open console–cannot connect to the site</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/10/29/configmgr-sccm-2012-wont-open-consolecannot-connect-to-the-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 09:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/10/29/configmgr-sccm-2012-wont-open-consolecannot-connect-to-the-site/</guid>
      <description>So, we have started our migration from ConfigMgr 2007 R2 to SCCM 2012. We have installed the new site and now we have started building the required collections as we are using a mix of old collections from ConfigMgr 2007 ( a lot of the built-in collections that are present in ConfigMgr 2007 are NOT present in SCCM 2012. So of course, copy and paste of the Query language is quite useful and this is one of the first things I would do when you are in the process of a SCCM Migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inactive Incidents–E-mail assigned to User</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/10/10/inactive-incidentse-mail-assigned-to-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 07:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/10/10/inactive-incidentse-mail-assigned-to-user/</guid>
      <description>Just recently I was looking for a way to notify users about Inactive incidents as I have some departments that tend to ignore their work items and an e-mail about their “untouched” incidents seems to motivate them. So after some searching I found this scriptfrom Andreas BaumgartenPlease note : I only modified this script to extend its use to other Statuses to be monitored. All credit for the script goes entirely to Andreas BaumgartenCode is below[sourcecode language=”powershell”]# Configure Last Modified Days Before</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Requests – Re-assignment notification</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/07/09/service-requests-re-assignment-notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 05:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/07/09/service-requests-re-assignment-notification/</guid>
      <description>So, in an effort to get my business ready for Service Requests as we use mainly Incidents and we are beginning our journey into Service Requests and differentiating between Service Requests (day to day operations) and Incidents (something is broken), I needed to reproduce a workflow to notify the “AssignedToUser” when a new Service Request is assigned to him or her. I already had a downloaded Management Pack for Incident Re-assignment notifications which was modified for my purposes, so this was a good place to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is my Service Manager so slow?</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/06/26/why-is-my-service-manager-so-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 07:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/06/26/why-is-my-service-manager-so-slow/</guid>
      <description>So, I have been running Service Manager for quite some time now. From SCSM 2010 to SCSM SP1 and most of the CU’s before I upgraded to SCSM 2012 Beta and RC and then to RTM (with the help of a Microsoft TAP Program). Service Manager is now quite entrenched in our business and has been running quite well for a very long time. However, a little while ago we began to experience performance issues with the Console and the logging of calls and the application of Workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing System Centre Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/06/13/installing-system-centre-orchestrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 12:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/06/13/installing-system-centre-orchestrator/</guid>
      <description>So, just recently I decided to install System Centre Orchestrator. It appears easy enough if you follow the Technet articles. This addresses the need for Service Accounts and the permissions needed by these accounts and there functions. It also helps you to size and decide the Orchestrator installation type that would best suit your environment. It helps you to decide the best way to break the components if you want to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading from SCSM 2010 / SCSM 2012 PRE-RTM to SCSM 2012 RTM</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/04/30/upgrading-from-scsm-2010-scsm-2012-pre-rtm-to-scsm-2012-rtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 07:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2012/04/30/upgrading-from-scsm-2010-scsm-2012-pre-rtm-to-scsm-2012-rtm/</guid>
      <description>So, You are now ready to take the plunge and upgrade to SCSM 2012 RTM as it now “publically” available.
There is great documentation, obviously, on TECHNET. I have however found out a few other things which will helpfully make your transition a little easier. I have found that the following can cause some complications and how to “mitigate” these if you will.
Service Manager 2010
Connectors – Please make sure that your connectors are NOT running while you do the upgrade, the upgrade will work, however your connectors will run and attempt to catch up with itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Pre-Production environment for Service Manager 2010</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/11/09/building-a-pre-production-environment-for-service-manager-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 06:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/11/09/building-a-pre-production-environment-for-service-manager-2010/</guid>
      <description>I can now post this, as my steps have been published on the SCSM Team Engineering site here.
Have you ever needed to build a pre-production environment to test an update or work on workflows, I did.
Thought I would share this and maybe it would help someone else as well.
It at the moment consists of the following.
1 Domain Controller
1 Management Server
1 Data Warehouse Server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled reports with SCSM Data Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/10/26/scheduled-reports-with-scsm-data-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 10:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/10/26/scheduled-reports-with-scsm-data-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>Hi All,
I know it has been a little while.
The reports built into Service Manager are great, however when you try to get a bit creative and automate some of the reports, you are going to run into some issues. So to work around theses issues, I did the following.
Create a custom report from SQL Reporting Services and modified for my needs, I was focusing more on “Incident Analyst” and I was looking for a breakdown of the number of Incidents per Analysts in a week period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some more trick and things I have learnt with Service Manager 2010 SP1</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/03/31/some-more-trick-and-things-i-have-learnt-with-service-manager-2010-sp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 10:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/03/31/some-more-trick-and-things-i-have-learnt-with-service-manager-2010-sp1/</guid>
      <description>When creating a new Self Service portal, ensure that you log onto on the server using your “Service Manager” Account, the account configured when first creating the Service Manager Server. The portal will install and seem to work. However, when you open the Portal, you will get HTTP 500.
  When configuring your Data Warehouse, ensure that the Database name has no “–“ in the name as this is NOT supported by the Reporting Component of Service Manager 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Manager 2010 SP1 Custom Portal</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/03/29/service-manager-2010-sp1-custom-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 08:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/03/29/service-manager-2010-sp1-custom-portal/</guid>
      <description>It has been a little bit of a busy while for me. However, I finally found the time to complete the Custom Service Manager Portal, I have not as yet implemented custom graphics. The end result is great, it has a far cleaner look and like the post says, feels a lot more like SharePoint. Finally you can see a shot of it, NOT in a document. If i can do it, so can anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Manager and all the tricks I have learnt</title>
      <link>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/03/04/service-manager-and-all-the-tricks-i-have-learnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 09:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudadventures.fskelly.com/2011/03/04/service-manager-and-all-the-tricks-i-have-learnt/</guid>
      <description>It has been some time since I last blogged, been a really nutty time. however i will make the time to blog and hopefully who ever reads this, it will be of assistance to them.
The lessons I have learned thus far.
  Label all your workflows properly, this cost me a case with MS Support only to discover that all workflows and NOW notifications are grouped together. I am assuming that this is to aid the troubleshooting process should something go wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
